♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 17=
Seal all their shops!
Xiaosheng Society?
I'll make him a like a headless bird.
You shouldn't have come to me now.
Things have come to this,
and you can still sit tight?
This is your brilliant plan?
The case back then has been exposed.
Jiang Chun'er is now
the new chamber head.
The Xiaosheng Society
is under public attack.
And the Buddha Head and phoenix crown
are still missing.
The only thing we can do now is to wait.
Wait? Wait until Fengcheng
spirals completely out of control?
I'm telling you,
if you can't come up with a useful plan,
the Japanese will be the first
to come after you.
We are not at a dead end yet.
Don't rush to assign blame.
By "wait", I mean my private army
will soon return to Fengcheng.
Then I'll have the power
to regain my military authority
as the Governor.
Why should I still trust you?
Do you have any other options?
Don't forget
that you and I
have long been in the same boat.
Only if you help me
regain military power
will I help you protect
the Xiaosheng Society
and find the phoenix crown
and Buddha Head.
Tomorrow my private army
will return to Fengcheng.
To make it work,
it still needs your cooperation.
Start with this Rong Xiaonan.
The phoenix crown
is definitely connected to him.
And only he knows the whereabouts
of the Buddha Head.
As for what comes next,
you should know what to do.
Once I help you find the phoenix crown
and Buddha Head,
I hope you honor our deal.
Rest assured.
Mr. Rong,
too much has happened recently,
and I'm always anxious
and scared for no reason.
I'm afraid of losing important things
or important people.
The Governor is utterly devoted to you.
You'll never lose him.
This is the keepsake
your mother left you.
Are you sure you want to bury it?
Going through my mother's belongings,
I suddenly realized
that her greatest wish in life
was to share a bed in life
and a grave in death
with Head Rong.
Fortunately, the truth about what
she went through has come to light.
But those past days
can never be brought back.
This phoenix crown carries all the past
and her unfulfilled longings.
Now, I shall let it stay here
in this forest
with all in the past.
It can rest in peace like my mother.
For me, it's also
letting go of obsessions.
Sometimes, letting go of obsessions
is a blessing
for both yourself and others.
Mr. Rong, this fleeting life
is like a dream within a dream,
and worldly matters
are like whispers in wind.
So let the wind
take all worldly matters with it.
Alright.
In that case,
it's time to return this
to its rightful owner.
(To Miss Jiang)
I want to talk to my mother
a little more.
Governor,
from files that the Xiaosheng Society
thugs hadn't destroyed yet,
we discovered more of their crimes.
And the case from eight years ago
is indeed connected to Xu Fan,
who was police chief back then.
Xu Fan.
Ghost!
Stay away!
When you killed my mother,
didn't you ever think a vengeful ghost
would come back for you?
Vengeful ghost? You've come
to take my life, haven't you?
Vengeful ghost,
I didn't kill anyone.
I hit it.
Like this.
We finally found you.
Get him!
Move!
Let go of me!
Behave!
Move!
Don't kill me,
vengeful ghost.
Please, Lord Vengeful Ghost.
Don't kill me,
vengeful ghost.
You'an?
Since you don't have a proper name,
from now on,
take my surname.
You'an.
You'an,
I'm your father.
You won't kill me, right?
You'an.
Before, to repay what you call
your ten years of bringing me up,
even though you were utterly evil,
I still let you live on.
But now,
even if you act like a dog,
you're not worthy of that.
I didn't do it.
It was the Xiaosheng Society
and Du Xiaolin.
They forced me to do it.
Spare me.
(Could they really be colluding
with the Japanese?)
(So they have such powerful weapons.)
I don't know.
Where are the Xiaosheng Society's
weapons?
I only know there's a ship.
A very big one.
And it seems to be smoking.
If you don't tell the truth,
you'll die right now!
I really don't know.
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪